Rubinow, Isaac Max Papers 5616
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Correspondence in Russian (summary translations) (folder 8 of 17), 1906 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: Letter #1, Letter (Box 11, Folder 17)
    Many from editors.
  - Item 2: Letter #2, 1906; Letter (Box 11, Folder 17)
    Two letters (1906) from a watchmaker named Sapozhnik about emigration.
  - Item 3: Letter #3, Letter (Box 11, Folder 17)
    Letter about a lecture for Social-Democrats.
  - Item 4: Letter #4, Letter (Box 11, Folder 17)
    Three letters, nearly illegible, reacting to articles and setting a meeting.
- Correspondence in Russian (summary translations) (folder 9 of 17) (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: Letter #1, Letter (Box 11, Folder 18)
    Editorial.
  - Item 2: Letter #2, Letter (Box 11, Folder 18)
    Packet of letters from a colleague. Reaction to articles, talk about publishers, etc.
- Correspondence in Russian (summary translations) (folder 10 of 17), 1907-1925 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Item 1: Letter #1, Letter (Box 11, Folder 19)
    The true story of domestics, from a domestic in English.
  - Item 2: Letter #2, Letter (Box 11, Folder 19)
    Fan letter, English.
  - Item 3: Letter #3, Letter (Box 11, Folder 19)
    A few letters from an acquaintance: addresses, information on social insurance (1920).
  - Item 4: Letter #4, 1907; Letter (Box 11, Folder 19)
    Thank-you note from a reporter (English) 1907.
  - Item 5: Letter #5, Letter (Box 11, Folder 19)
    From Moscow - name illegible - "how are you, please write".
  - Item 6: Letter #6, 1915; Letter (Box 11, Folder 19)
    1915 from NYU - Social Insurance.
  - Item 7: Letter #7, 1914; Letter (Box 11, Folder 19)
    "Thank you for the manuscript" (German) 1914.
  - Item 8: Letter #8, Letter (Box 11, Folder 19)
    From Olivia Leventritt. English. About the Gary plan (?.
  - Item 9: Letter #9, Letter (Box 11, Folder 19)
    From Warsaw - friendly correspondence, when we last met, etc.
  - Item 10: Letter #10, 1922; Letter (Box 11, Folder 19)
    From Zionist Organization, London - Request for help for a young Jewish officer wrongfully detained 1922.
  - Item 11: Letter #11, Letter (Box 11, Folder 19)
    From Jewish Blind Institute "Thank-you" note in Yiddish or Hebrew attached.
  - Item 12: Letter #12, Letter (Box 11, Folder 19)
    From "American Zionist Medical Unit in Palestine" discusses Rubinov's ties with the organization, I think (almost illegible).
  - Item 13: Letter #13, Letter (Box 11, Folder 19)
    From Paris - about the writer's move there (no date).
  - Item 14: Letter #14, 1921; Letter (Box 11, Folder 19)
    1921 - in English, discusses politics of the Zonist movement - end of letter missing.
  - Item 15: Letter #15, 1925; Letter (Box 11, Folder 19)
    Dr. Z. Bychowski 1925 Warsaw discusses a "question" referred to in Rubinov's letter. - Zionist politics.
  - Item 16: Letter #16, Letter (Box 11, Folder 19)
    Letterhead Hotel Ansonia - from a new emigrant, who has brought something for Rubinov.
  - Item 17: Letter #17, Letter (Box 11, Folder 19)
    From "Beyrouth", Syria - English - a thank-you note from J.W. Jenks.
- Correspondence in Russian (summary translations) (folder 11 of 17) (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Item 1: Letter #1, Letter (Box 11, Folder 20)
    Many letters from editors.
  - Item 2: Letter #2, Letter (Box 11, Folder 20)
    Packet of letters from Pereferkovich - a visit to Rubinov - comments about articles - about the rich Jewish society he moved in in Tannersville "they're not very intellectual".
  - Item 3: Letter #3, Letter (Box 11, Folder 20)
    Letters from N. Pinkus - from Warsaw and Gottingen mostly about Social Insurance.
  - Item 4: Letter #4, Letter (Box 11, Folder 20)
    2 letters Holland House letterhead - they deal with taking some books back to Moscow.
- Correspondence in Russian (summary translations) (folder 12 of 17), 1892-1903 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Item 1: Letter #1, 1903; Letter (Box 11, Folder 21)
    Letters from Livshits - an the worsening 1903 condition of Jews in Russia - advice on emigration.
  - Item 2: Letter #2, 1892; Letter (Box 11, Folder 21)
    2 letters from "Leon" 1892 one letter from a vacation "It's beautiful, wish you were here".
- Correspondence in Russian (summary translations) (folder 13 of 17), 1893-1895 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Item 1: Letter #1, 1893-1895; Letter (Box 11, Folder 22)
    Packet of friendly correspondence with Roza Markus 1893-95.
  - Item 2: Letter #2, 1894-1895; Letter (Box 11, Folder 22)
    Many letters from L. Markus - 1894-95 - friendly correspondence.
  - Item 3: Letter #3, Letter (Box 11, Folder 22)
    Letters from editors and colleagues.
  - Item 4: Letter #4, Letter (Box 11, Folder 22)
    Letters from Russian Embassy about Rubinov's request to visit Russia.
- Correspondence in Russian (summary translations) (folder 14 of 17) (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Item 1: Letter #1, Letter (Box 11, Folder 23)
    Letters from the Central Committee of the Jewish Colonization Society in St. Petersburg, dealing with Rubinov's assistance to them in the form of information for Jews wishing to emigrate.
- Correspondence in Russian (summary translations) (folder 15 of 17), 1892 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Item 1: Letter #1, Letter (Box 11, Folder 24)
    Letters from the editors of "Notes of the Moscow Municipal Council".
  - Item 2: Letter #2, 1892; Letter (Box 11, Folder 24)
    3 letters 1892 friendly correspondence with Ivasik.
- Correspondence in Russian (summary translations) (folder 16 of 17), 1903-1904 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Item 1: Letter #1, 1903-1904; Letter (Box 11, Folder 25)
    Two letters from Jews thinking of emigrating, asking for advice 1903 and 1904.
  - Item 2: Letter #2, Letter (Box 11, Folder 25)
    Two letters from Gafagovich (?), a colleague.
  - Item 3: Letter #3, 1904; Letter (Box 11, Folder 25)
    Postcard - 1904 from friends waiting for a ship in Trieste.
- Correspondence in Russian (summary translations) (folder 17 of 17) (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Item 1: Letter #1, Letter (Box 11, Folder 26)
    100 (?) letters from G. Wilenkin, Financial Agent of the Russian government, about money received from Russia, and also friendly meetings, etc.
  - Item 2: Letter #2, Letter (Box 11, Folder 26)
    Two letters, in English - replies to requested information.
  - Item 3: Letter #3, Letter (Box 11, Folder 26)
    Two telegrams about crop conditions.
- I.M. Rubinow, Collection (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Is Agriculture the Solution (Box 12, Folder 2)
- The Credo of A Jewish Social Worker (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Death Benefits (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Divorce and After (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Employment and Health (Box 12, Folder 6)
- European Plans of Social Insurance [folder 1 of 6] (Box 12, Folder 7)
- European Plans of Social Insurance [folder 2 of 6] (Box 12, Folder 8)
- European Plans of Social Insurance [folder 3 of 6] (Box 12, Folder 9)
- European Plans of Social Insurance [folder 4 of 6] (Box 12, Folder 10)
- European Plans of Social Insurance [folder 5 of 6] (Box 12, Folder 11)
- European Plans of Social Insurance [folder 6 of 6] (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Governments Obligation for Economic Security (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Health Insurance (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Hebraist Movement (Box 12, Folder 15)
- Hebrew University (Box 12, Folder 16)
- Intelligent Philanthropy (Box 12, Folder 17)
- Jewish Relief Work in the U.S., Future of (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Jewish Welfare Society; The Work of Jew in the American Academic World; Position of Jewish Point of View; Jewish Federation, The Work of; From the (Recent Economic Developments) Jewish Workman (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Jewish Trends, What About; Jewish Palestine, Health Problems of (Box 12, Folder 20)
- Jewish - Miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 21)
- Lundeen Bill (Box 12, Folder 22)
- Medical Report; Medicine Socialized; Mother's Pension:- (Box 12, Folder 23)
- Ohio Conditions (Box 12, Folder 24)
- Old Age Pensions (Box 12, Folder 25)
- Permanent Partial Disability [folder 1 of 3] (Box 12, Folder 26)
- Permanent Partial Disability [folder 2 of 3] (Box 12, Folder 27)
- Permanent Partial Disability [folder 3 of 3] (Box 12, Folder 28)
- Philadelphia Housing (Box 12, Folder 29)
- Place of Health and Unemployment Insurance in; Problem of Domestic Service (Box 12, Folder 30)
- Prophecies of Marx (Box 12, Folder 31)
- Public Relief (Box 12, Folder 32)
- Quest for Security (Box 12, Folder 33)
- Rate of Weekly Benefits (Box 12, Folder 34)
- Relations Between Public Welfare and Jewish Social Work; Relations Between Social and Business Statistics (Box 12, Folder 35)
- Revolt of Middle Age (Box 12, Folder 36)
- Rich Man, Poor Man; Rural and Urban Possibilities in Palestine (Box 12, Folder 37)
- Social Insurance (Box 12, Folder 38)
- Social Insurance As A Program of Social Work; Social Insurance Unified (Box 12, Folder 39)
- Social Security Act (Box 12, Folder 40)
- Social Security Act and Intergroup Relations (Box 12, Folder 41)
- Social Security Act - Facts and Fancies (Box 12, Folder 42)
- Social Security Act - Promise or Program (Box 12, Folder 43)
- Social Security Act - Planning For (Box 12, Folder 44)
- Social Work and Social Progress; Social Worker and Law Enforcement (Box 12, Folder 45)
- State Pools and Merit Rating (Box 12, Folder 46)
- Statistician Looks At Marriage (Box 12, Folder 47)
- Unemployment Insurance [folder 1 of 5] (Box 12, Folder 48)
- Unemployment Insurance [folder 2 of 5] (Box 12, Folder 49)
- Unemployment Insurance [folder 3 of 5] (Box 12, Folder 50)
- Unemployment Insurance [folder 4 of 5] (Box 12, Folder 51)
- Unemployment Insurance [folder 5 of 5] (Box 12, Folder 52)
- Unity In Israel (Box 12, Folder 53)
- Versus Complex (Box 12, Folder 54)
- Why the Federal Government Should Contribute to Unemployment Insurance (Box 12, Folder 55)
- Handwritten Manuscript in Russian [folder 1 of 2], 1904 (Box 12, Folder 56)
  2 file folders
- Handwritten Manuscript in Russian [folder 2 of 2], 1904 (Box 12, Folder 57)
- Handwritten Manuscript in Russian, 1912 (Box 12, Folder 58)
- Correspondence re manuscripts [folder 1 of 3] (Box 12, Folder 59)
- Correspondence re manuscripts [folder 2 of 3] (Box 12, Folder 60)
- Correspondence re manuscripts [folder 3 of 3] (Box 12, Folder 61)
- Miscellaneous notes, statistics (Box 12, Folder 62)
- Miscellaneous reports (Box 12, Folder 63)
- Miscellaneous Speeches and official statements (Box 12, Folder 64)
- Miscellaneous [folder 1 of 4] (Box 12, Folder 65)
- Miscellaneous [folder 2 of 4] (Box 12, Folder 66)
- Miscellaneous [folder 3 of 4] (Box 12, Folder 67)
- Miscellaneous [folder 4 of 4] (Box 12, Folder 68)
- Clippings, 1902-1907 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  Bound volume
- Clippings, 1902-1907 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Draft of Quest for Security (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Draft of Quest for Security (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Municipal Studies, 1906-1910 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  Bound volume, in Russian
- Municipal Studies, 1906-1910 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Municipal Studies, 1906-1910 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous Articles (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Articles-Statistical, 1902-1918 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Russian Wheat, 1906 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- California Social Insurance Commission Report (Mss.) (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Statistics of Manufacturing Industries in European Russia, lrl8 (Box 14, Folder 12)
- Clippings (Box 14, Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous pamphlets, articles and periodicals (Box 14, Folder 14)
- Miscellaneous correspondence _re_ articles (Box 14, Folder 15)
- Clippings, 1908-1914 (Box 14, Folder 16)
- Miscellaneous and Personal - Economic Conditions of Jews in the U.S., 1930-1934 (Box 14, Folder 17)
- Miscellaneous reprints of articles (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Reprints (Box 15, Folder 2)
- in Russian (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Insurance Articles (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Insurance Articles (Box 15, Folder 5)
- American Life Insurance (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Immigration (Box 15, Folder 7)
- in Russian (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous newspaper clippings (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Clippings (Box 16, Folder 10)
- Clippings (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Personal Clippings and Miscellaneous re Unemployment Insurance, id) Social Security, 1934-1935 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  vols.
- Personal Clippings and Miscellaneous re Unemployment Insurance, id) Social Security, 1934-1935 (Box 16, Folder 13)
- Family Schedules (Box 17, Folder 1-4)
  Includes form letters and completed forms of Rubinow's relatives relative to a study undertaken by him
- Income Tax Return Form, 1927 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Lecture Announcements (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Membership Cards (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Menorah Conference - Remarks, 1927 (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous (Box 17, Folder 9)
- New Year's Greeting Cards (Box 17, Folder 10-11)
- Obituaries, Memorial (Box 17, Folder 12)
- Photographs of Rubinow (Box 17, Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous Publications (Box 17, Folder 14)
- Restricted Correspondence, 1925-1935 (Box 18, Folder All)
  91 letters
- Images digitized from the collection. (Box 19)